Guide to the Oskar Morgenstern Papers, 1866-1992 and undated RL.10033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2006-0067), 22 boxes, 1 ovsz. folder
  - Writings by Morgenstern (Box 102)
    - Handworterbuch der Sozialwissenschaften, undated (Box 107)
    - Index to Unknown, undated (Box 107)
    - Insiders and Outsiders in Industrial Research, 1969 (Box 107)
    - International Gold Standard Re-interpreted, 1946 (Box 107)
    - John von Neumann e Oskar Morgenstern, 1971 (Box 107)
    - Kapital, 1932 (Box 107)
    - La Introduzione e la Abolizione del Controllo Dei Cambi Esteri in Austria, 1937 (Box 107)
    - La Teoria de los Juegos y Del Comportamiento Economico, 1955 (Box 107)
    - La Teoria Dei Giochi e del Comportamento Economico, 1951 (Box 107)
    - La Valeur du Programme Spatial des Etats-Unis: Etude Economique, 1969 (Box 107)
    - Las Ciencias Sociales en el Umbral de Nuevas Evoluciones,1966 (Box 107)
    - L'attitude de la Nature Et. Le Comportement Rationnel, 1967 (Box 107)
    - League of Nations - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 107)
    - League of Nations - Materials, 1938-1939 (Box 107)
    - League of Nations - Various Printed Materials, 1938-1939 (Box 107)
    - L'economie est-elle une Science Exacte?, 1971 (Box 107)
    - Les Fondements Philosophiques des Systemes Economiques, undated (Box 108)
    - L'Etude des Conjonctures en Autriche, 1935 (Box 108)
    - Limite Al Empleo de Las Mathematics en la Ciencia Ecpmp,oca,1965 (Box 108)
    - Limiti e Condizinoi dei Programmi Economici, undated (Box 108)
    - Limits of Economics (Xerox), 1937 (Box 108)
    - Limits to the Uses of Mathematics in Economics (Reprint), 1963 (Box 108)
    - Logistik und Sozialwissenschaften, 1936 (Box 108)
    - Long Term Planning with Models of Static and Dynamic Open Expanding Economies by O. Morgenstern and G.L. Thompson and Strategic Allocations and Integral Games by O. Morgenstern, 1972 (Box 108)
    - Long Term Planning with Models of Static and Dynamic Open Expanding Economies by O. Morgenstern and G.L. Thompson, 1972 (Box 108)
    - Long Term Projections of Power by Klavs P. Heiss, Klavs Knorr, Oskar Morgenstern (Xerox), 1973 (Box 108)
    - Manuscript- Handwritten, undated (Box 108)
    - Manuscript Part 2, 1st Draft, undated (Box 108)
    - Mathematica Economic Analysis of the Space Shuttle System, 1972 (Box 108)
    - Mathematica: the Limits of Economics, 1937 (Box 108)
    - Mathematical Theory of Expanding and Contracting Economies by Oskar Morgenstern, Gerald L. Thompson (Xerox), 1976 (Box 108)
    - Mathematics and the Social Sciences: Limits to the Use of Mathematics in Economics, 1963 (Box 108)
    - Mineral Statistics, undated (Box 108)
    - Miscellaneous Figures, undated (Box 108)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 108)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 108)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1950, 1955, 1961, 1962, undated (Box 109)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, undated (Box 109)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, undated (Box 109)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, undated (Box 109)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 109)
    - Mitteilungen, 1956 (Box 109)
    - Modelling in Complex Situation with Soft Infortmation- Group Report edited by Herman Wold, 1975 (Box 109)
    - Monopoly and Competition in Industry and Labor edited by John A. Krout, 1939 (Box 109)
    - Morgenstern on Economic Forecasting, 1929 (Box 109)
    - National Income and Growth, undated (Box 110)
    - National Income Statistics, undated (Box 110)
    - National Income Statistics, undated (Box 110)
    - Nature's Attitude and Rationale Behavior, 1966 (Box 110)
    - Naval Research Logistics Quarterly: a Note on an Open Expanding Economy Model, vol.16, no.4 by O. Morgenstern and G.L. Thompson, 1969 (Box 110)
    - Naval Research Logistics Quarterly: a Note on an Open Expanding Economy Model, vol.19, no.3 by O. Morgenstern and G.L. Thompson, 1972 (Box 110)
    - Naval Research Logistics Quarterly: a Note on the Formulation of the Theory of Logistics, by O. Morgenstern, vol.2, no.3, 1955 (Box 110)
    - New Look at Economic Time Series Analysis, undated (Box 110)
    - New Look on Economic Time Series Analysis, 1961 (Box 110)
    - New Manuscript Part 1 - has been revised (Box 110)
    - New Uses for the New Knowledge, 1968 (Box 110)
    - Note on the Formulation of the Study of Logistics, 1951 (Box 110)
    - Note on the Formulation of the Study of Logistics, 1955 (Box 110)
    - Note on the Role of Follow-Ups in the Naval Supply System, 1952 (Box 110)
    - Notes fo Accuracy Part I, 1962 (Box 110)
    - Notes on "Attrition, Shelters, and Recovery", undated (Box 111)
    - Notes and Preliminary Manuscripts, undated (Box 111)
    - Notes: Gold (Active),undated (Box 111)
    - Notes: World Stock, Production and Consumption of Gold, undated (Box 111)
    - Nuove Considerazioni Sulla Teoria Della Domanda, 1952 (Box 111)
    - Obituary: John Von Neumann 1903-1957 (Reprint from the Economic Journal), 1958 (Box 111)
    - Offene Probleme der Kosten-Und Ertragstheorie, 1931 (Box 111)
    - Okonometrische Berechungen im Groben, undated (Box 111)
    - Oligopoly, Monopolistic Competition, and the Theory of Games (Reprint from American Economic Review Proceedings), 1948 (Box 111)
    - On Some Criticisms of Game Theory, 1964 (Box 111)
    - On the Accuracy of Economic Observations (Xerox),1950 (Box 111)
    - On the Application of Game Theory to Economics, 1962 (Box 111)
    - On the International Spread of Business Cycles (Reprint from the Journal of Political Economy), 1943 (Box 111)
    - Oskar Morgenstern Important Papers, 1954, undated (Box 111)
    - Other Reviews: Granger and Morgenstern etc., undated (Box 111)
    - Pareto Optimum and Economic Organization (2 versions), 1964 (Box 111)
    - Part 2 Chapter 2, undated (Box 112)
    - Part 2, Final Drafts, Inserts, undated (Box 112)
    - Part II MS, undated (Box 112)
    - Political Conjecture in Military Planning by Klaus Knorr and O. Morgenstern ,1968 (Box 112)
    - Political Economist Views: The Navy/Industry Look at the Future, 1961 (Box 112)
    - Population, undated (Box 112)
    - Price Statistics, undated (Box 112)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, Vol. XXXIX, No.28, 1939 (Box 112)
    - Private and Public Consumption by O. Morgenstern and L. Thompson, undated (Box 112)
    - Proceeding of a Correspondence on Inter-industrial Relations Held at Driebergen, Holland, undated (Box 112)
    - Production, 1961 (Box 112)
    - Project Harbor: Postattack Recovery Program (Panel D), 1963 (Box 112)
    - Project Harbor: Postattack Survival and Recovery- Social and Economic (Panel D Subgroup), 1963 (Box 112)
    - Prolegomena to a Theory of Organization, 1951 (Box 112)
    - Qualitative und Quantitative Konjunkturschung, 1928 (Box 112)
    - Question of National Defense (Chapter 1-3),undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Chapter 1-4),undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Chapter 4-6),undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Chapter 4-6),undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Chapter 5-9), undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Edited manuscript from publisher) Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Edited manuscript from publisher) Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Edited manuscript from publisher) Chapters 6-11, undated (Box 113)
    - Question of National Defense (Edited manuscript from publisher) Chapters 6-11, undated (Box 113)
    - Qui Numerare Incipit Errare Incipit, 1964 (Box 113)
    - Qui Numerare Incipit Errare Incipit, 1963 (Box 113)
    - Qui Numerare Incipit Errare Incipit, Fortune, 1963 (Box 113)
    - Recent Advances in Game Theory,1961 (Box 114)
    - Revisions of Unknown Book, undated (Box 114)
    - Revue des Travaux de I'Academie, 1969 (Box 114)
    - Science and Defense: Some Critical Thoughts on Military Research and Development by Klaus Knorr and O. Morgenstern, 1965 (Box 114)
    - Science and Defense: Some Critical Thoughts on Military Research and Development Feb. 1965 by Klaus Knorr and Oskar Morgenstern, 1965 (Box 114)
    - Science and Defense: Some Critical Thoughts on Military Research and Development Mar. 1965 by Klaus Knorr and Oskar Morgenstern, 1965 (Box 114)
    - Scientist and Citizen, 1966 (Box 114)
    - Shaping the Future:Gaston Berger and the Concept of Prospective edited by Andre Cournand, Maurice Levy with a Foreword by Morgenstern (xerox) n.d. (Box 114)
    - Sobre la Exactitud de las Observaciones Economomicas, 1970 (Box 114)
    - Some Reflections on Utility, 1974 (Box 114)
    - Some Thoughts on Bearing on National Defense Policy, 1958 (Box 114)
    - Sonderdruck aus Alfred Eugen Ott Preistheorie,undated (Box 114)
    - Soziologie und Soziologiestudium, 1966 (Box 114)
    - Speech by Dr. Oskar Morgenstern at Managers' Development Conference, undated (Box 114)
    - Sperimentazione e Calcolo Su Vasta Scala in Economica, undated (Box 114)
    - Spieltheorie Als Allgemeine Theorie des Machtkonfliktes,undated (Box 114)
    - Spieltheorie und Wirtschaftschaft, 1965 (Box 114)
    - Spieltheorie: Ein Neues Paradigma der Sozialwissenschaft, 1968 (Box 114)
    - Spieltheorie: Ein neves Paradigma der Sozialwissenschaft, 1968 (Box 114)
    - Spieltheorie: Ein neves Paradigma der Sozialwissenschaft, undated (Box 114)
    - Spieltheorie-Ein neues Paradigma fur die Sozialwissenschaften, 1967 (Box 114)
    - Stolnitz,undated (Box 114)
    - Strategic Allocation and Integral Games (from Advances in Game Theory-Editor E. Vilkas), 1973 (Box 114)
    - Strategy Manuscript, undated (Box 114)
    - Strategy Manuscript, undated (Box 114)
    - Studi di Metodologia Economica, 1955 (Box 115)
    - Sull'accuratezza Della Statistiche Del Reddito Nazionale e del Progresso Economico, 1963 (Box 115)
    - Summary: the Stability of Inverses of Input-Output Matrices by Oskar Morgenstern and Max A. Woodbury, 1950 (Box 115)
    - Symmetric Solutions of Competition and Collusion in Bilateral Markets by O. Morgenstern and G. Schwodiauer, 1975 (Box 115)
    - Symmetric Solutions of Some Generalization of n-Person Games by J. von Neumann and O. Morgenstern, 1946 (Box 115)
    - Symmetric Solutions of Some Generalization of n-Person Games by J. von Neumann and O. Morgenstern, 1961 (Box 115)
    - Theorie des Spiels, 1949 (Box 115)
    - Theory of Games (from Scientific American), 1949 (Box 115)
    - Theory of Games and Economic Behavior by John Von Neumann and Oskar Morgenstern, 1944 (Box 115)
    - Theory of Games and Economic Behavior by John Von Neumann and Oskar Morgenstern, 1944 (Box 115)
    - Theory of implementation of Cost and Benefit Analysis of Transportation Systems: The NECTP, 1969 Aug., undated (Box 115)
    - Thirteen Critical Points in Contemporary Economic Theory:an Interpretation and Descriptive, Predictive and Normative Theory, 1972 (Box 115)
    - Thirteen Critical Points in Contemporary Economic Theory:an Interpretation, 1972 (Box 115)
    - Time Moment in Value Theory, undated (Box 115)
    - Toal Gold Stock, Gold in Central Banks and Gold in Circulation for Great Britain, France, Germany and U.S., 1945 (Box 115)
    - Translation of Perfect Foresight and Economic Equilibrium, 1935 (Box 115)
    - Trece Puntos Criticos de la Teoria Economicq Contemporanea: Una Interpretacion, 1974 (Box 116)
    - Trend Analysis of Discrete Time Series, undated (Box 116)
    - Un Modele de Croissance en Economie Ouverte, 1971 (Box 116)
    - Unemployment: Analysis of Factors (Reprint from American Economic Review Proceedings), 1941 (Box 116)
    - University, Fall 1965,No.26, 1965 (Box 116)
    - University, Summer 1964, No.21: On Conjecturing about Our Future, 1964 (Box 116)
    - University, Summer 1968, No.37: Economic Results of Space Exploration, 1968 (Box 116)
    - Unknown Book: Chapter V, "Limitation of War", undated (Box 116)
    - Unnamed Folder, undated (Box 116)
    - Unnamed Folder, undated (Box 116)
    - Unnamed Folder, undated (Box 116)
    - Unnamed Folder, undated (Box 116)
    - Unnamed Folder, undated (Box 116)
    - Unpublished Gold Material Latest Version, 1959 (Box 116)
    - Validity of International Gold Movement Statistics, 1955 (Box 116)
    - Various Papers on Military Policy, 1964 (Box 116)
    - Volkommene Voraussicht und Wirtschaftliches Gleichgewicht, 1935 (Box 116)
    - Von Neumann Model,undated (Box 116)
    - Von Neumann, John, 1968 (Box 116)
    - Wahrung und Preise1936 (Box 116)
    - Weltwirtschaftliches Archiv, 1931 (Box 116)
    - When is a Problem of Economic Policy Solvable?, 1953 (Box 116)
    - Worth of the Space Program: Economics, 1967 (Box 116)
    - Zeitschrift Fur Nationalokonomie, various years (Box 116)
  - Writings by Others (Box 117)
    - Aerospace Engineering vol.20, No.12, 1961 (Box 117)
    - Agricultural Statistics, 1949-1956 (Box 117)
    - American Statistician, vol.18, no.3, 1964 (Box 117)
    - Astronautics and Aeronautics, 1968 (Box 117)
    - Bau, 1967 (Box 117)
    - Bau, 1968 (Box 117)
    - Boletin del Banco Central de Venezuela, 1949 (Box 117)
    - Boletin del Banco Central de Venezuela, 1951 (Box 117)
    - Boletin del Banco Central de Venezuela, 1953 (Box 117)
    - Book Review: Mathematical Economics (Reprinted from the Southern Economic Journal), 1958 (Box 117)
    - Book Reviews edited by Oscar Krisen Buros (Reprint from the Journal of the American Statistical, 1947 (Box 117)
    - Business and Soceity Review, Spring 1977, No.21, 1977 (Box 117)
    - Capital Formation, 1938 (Box 117)
    - Controlling Technology Democratically by Arthur Kantrowitz, 1975 (Box 117)
    - Cowles Commission for Research in Economics Report, 1948-1949 (Box 117)
    - Czechoslovak Multistage Long-Term Planning Models in Centralized and Decentralized Management by A. Lassicak, I. Rendek, J. Danco, 1966 (Box 117)
    - Economists by Leonard Silk, 1976 (Box 117)
    - Energy Policy Evaluaytion Edited by Dilip R. Limaye (Xerox), undated (Box 117)
    - Estimates of the Capital Structure of American Industries, 1939 (Box 117)
    - Existence of Equilibrium in an Open Expanding Economy Model by Jerry Los, undated (Box 118)
    - Experiments with Input-Output Models by A. Ghosh, 1959 (Box 118)
    - Fallacies of Personality Testing Fortune Sept, 1954 (Box 118)
    - First Report of the Time Series Project - Clive W.J. Granger, 1960 Feb. (Box 118)
    - Forum for Contemporary History, 1974 (Box 118)
    - Fuzzy Sets in Multiple Criteria Decision-Making by Jean-Marie Blin, 1976 (Box 118)
    - Game Theory from Dictionary of the History of Ideas, Vol.II, 1973 (Box 118)
    - Game Theory Reviews, undated (Box 118)
    - General Discussion on Past and Future of the von Neumann Model (Box 118)
    - History of the Theory of Informatin by E. Colin Cherry, 1951 (Box 118)
    - Internal Demandfor Gold Great Britain, undated (Box 118)
    - Investment Tax Credit Controversy-William T. Hogan, Frank Koelble, undated (Box 118)
    - Jules Dupuit and the Early Theory of Marginal Cost Pricing by R.B. Ekelund, Jr., 1968 (Box 118)
    - Kyklos (xerox) vol. XXV, no.4, 1972 (Box 118)
    - Kyklos vol. XVI no.1, 1963 (Box 118)
    - Kyklos vol. XVII no.1, 1964 (Box 118)
    - Kyklos, vol.III, no. 4,1949 (Box 118)
    - La Metodologia di Oskar Morgenstern by Ferdinando di Fenizio, 1952 (Box 118)
    - Life International,1960 (Box 118)
    - Linear Assignment Formulation of the Multiattribute Decision Problem by Jean-Marie Blin (Xerox), 1976 (Box 118)
    - Measuring Noise Color - John W. Tukey and R.W. Hamming, 1949 Dec. (Box 118)
    - Measuring Noise Color by John W. Turkey, undated (Box 118)
    - Methods of Operations Research edited by Rudolf Henn, undated (Box 118)
    - Mining Statistics, undated (Box 118)
    - Mitteilungen, 1956 (Box 118)
    - Naval Research Logistics Quarterly, Vol.16, No.4, 1969 (Box 118)
    - Navy/Industry Look at the Future (from Aerospace Engineering), 1961 (Box 119)
    - New Look at Economic Time Series Analysis (Reprint from Money, Growth and Methodology), 1961 (Box 119)
    - New Look at Economic Time Series Analysis (Reprint from Money, Growth and Methodology), undated (Box 119)
    - News Clipping,undated (Box 119)
    - NIPALS Path Modelling with Latent Variables by Richard Noonan and Herman Wold, 1976 (Box 119)
    - Optimal Operations and Investments of the Firm by Russell G. Thompson and Melvin D. George, 1968 (Box 119)
    - Optimal Production, Investment and Output Inventory Controls for the Competitive Firm by Russell G. Thompson, Melvin D. George, Michael S. Proctor, 1968 (Box 119)
    - Oskar Morgenstern: Su Contribucion en la Construccion de la Economia Matematica y la Teoria Economica Del Siglo XX,1970 (Box 119)
    - Overview of the Mathmatical Theory of Games by William F. Lucas, 1972 (Box 119)
    - Path Models with Latent Variables:the NIPALS Approach by Herman Wold,1975 (Box 119)
    - Preliminary Discussion of the Logical Design of an Electronic Computing Instrument by Arthur W. Burks, Herman H. Goldstine and John von Neumann, 1946 (Box 119)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, Vol. LII, No.21, 1952 (Box 119)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, Vol. LVII, No.17, 1957 (Box 119)
    - Princeton Alumni Weekly, Vol. LXI, No.26, 1961 (Box 119)
    - Prognos, 1963, undated (Box 119)
    - Programming the Supply of a Strategic Material - Hermann F. Karemann, 1960 (Box 119)
    - Publication by Others, various years (Box 119)
    - Publications by Others, undated (Box 119)
    - Publications of the Statistical Institute for Economics Research, State Universityy of Sofia, 1935-1936 (Box 119)
    - Report of the New York Meeting (Reprinted from Econometrica), 1949 (Box 119)
    - Reprint from Input-Output Analysis: An Appraisal (Box 119)
    - Review of Essays ( Shubik Ed.), 1969 (Box 119)
    - Reviews of Oskar Morgenstern Festschrift, 1967 (Box 119)
    - Reviews of Oskar Morgenstern Festschrift,1972 (Box 120)
    - Role of Money in the Inflation Analysis by Helmut Frisch, 1975 (Box 120)
    - Sciences, Vol.12, No.9, 1972 (Box 120)
    - Scientific Ameircan, 1949 (Box 120)
    - Shapley Value as a von Neumann-Morgenstern Utility by Alvin E. Roth, undated (Box 120)
    - Soviet Nuclear Strategy: a Critical Apprasial edited by Robert Dickson Crane, 1963 (Box 120)
    - Soviet Statistics, 1950-1957 (Box 120)
    - Spectral Analysis Combing a Bartlett Window with an Associated Inner Window by Thomas H. Wonnacott, 1961 (Box 120)
    - Stable Sets and Stable Points of Set Valued Dynamic Systems by Michael Maschler and Bezalel Peleg, 1974 (Box 120)
    - Strategy-Proofness and Single -Peakness by Jean-Marie Blin and Mark A. Satterthwaite, 1975 (Box 120)
    - Studies in Deterrence: Validation Studies of the International Simulation by Charles F. Hermann and Margaret G. Hermann, 1963 (Box 120)
    - Technological Similarity and Aggregation in Input-Output Systems: A Cluster-Analytic Approach by Jean-Marie Blin and Claude Cohen, 1976 (Box 120)
    - Tests for Discrimination and Stationarity for Time Series - C.W.J. Granger, 1959 Mar., undated (Box 120)
    - Theory Absorption and the Testability of Economic Theory by Raymond Dacey, 1975 (Box 120)
    - Uncategorized Figures, undated (Box 120)
    - Universitas, 1966 (Box 120)
    - Vaclav Polak Mathmatical Politology, 1968 (Box 120)
    - Yale Law Journal (Box 120)
  - Bound Volumes (Box 121)
    - Fichtes, 1914 (Box 121)
    - Hegel, 1911 (Box 121)
    - Les Systems Socialistes,1902 (Box 121)
    - Mathematical Economics and Game Theory, 1977 (Box 121)
    - Spieltheorie und wirtschaftliches Verhalten,1946 (Box 121)
    - Spieltheorie und wirtschaftliches Verhalten,1973 (Box 121)
    - Spieltheorie und Wirtschaftliches,1963 (Box 121)
    - Turgot, 1913 (Box 121)
    - book: Giornale Degli Economisti e Rivista De Statistica, 1924 (Box 121)
  - Audiovisual materials (Box 122)
    - Economics Series: Economic Theory, 1964 (open reel audio tape) (Box 122)
    - John von Neumann, 1954 (open reel audio tape) (Box 122)
    - Talk at Scudder, 1962 (open reel audio tape) (Box 122)
    - 'Die Industrie: Zeitschrift fur die interessen der Osterreichischen industrie' Volume 48, number 33, 14 August 1948 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Draft of 'Spectral Analysis of Response Variation,' Carl Morgenstern, January 7 1969, Junior Independent Work (Oversize-folder 1)